Hi there.
Hello.
Good to see you, too.
Yeah, indeed. Nice thing. Nice to meet up.
Mm.
Ohh.
Before I start,
I've turned on the facilitator,
which should sort of...
do some meeting guidance,
some transcription. Yeah,
it's just announced itself.
Did you see that?
Yes, let's go.
Yes.
So it does a little bit of magic for us
so we don't have to do too much legwork.
What it doesn't do for us is to come up
with the ideas we need to have.
And.
And because I have had very little to do
with provider directories so far,
Yeah.
if either of you can give me a rundown
and...
EN.
and just throw some ideas at me,
then I'll get up to speed and will be
most valuable.
Kate.
So I have a suggestion around structure
of how we can go about this, but Paul,
Mm.
I'm going to be leaning on you for the
vision around this because I haven't been
involved in the actual selection of the
topic either.
I've done some work with provider
directories, so really happy to.
to put everything behind this.
But my suggestion would be, Paul,
if you could give us an idea of your...
your vision, if you like,
for where we would go with this.
I've got a few possible scenarios that
I've thought of that could be our main
focus, but I'd like to hear from you,
because that's the most important thing.
It has to be something useful to QH,
something that you have the vision for.
Once we've done that,
identify the use cases around that,
and then I can then probably help with
the bare bones of the resource analysis
and the profiling and that kind of thing.
The team breakdown.
that I would expect to have. But Paul,
are you happy to take the lead?
I'm offering my help,
but I just wanted to know if you're happy
to give us an idea of where we're going
with this.
Okay.
Didn't mean to put you on the spot, but...
Well, if it helps,
I can give you 4 possible scenarios and
No.
you can say which one you think.
Before you start this,
before we get the idea,
what's the whole point of this?
Connect the phone.
Oh, so how much I can feel that?
How much experience,
Okay.
like how much do you know about
Connectathon, what that is?
That gives me information as to where to
start, like at what level I should get in.
Well...
None.
None. OK, good. So.
Because fire is an interoperability
system.
Um...
The point is to actually make sure that
systems can connect.
You start drafting a standard that tells
you how to do it,
an implementation guide which tells you
how to do the interoperability.
But what's that worth if you don't
actually know whether systems can connect?
So the assumption is that the people who
a tender connectathon are aware of the
draught standard and think they've done
their work to a degree.
So they bring their computer systems,
clients or servers to the connectathon,
and then they sprint for one or two days
trying to make
connexions between the systems,
which gives you a matrix,
all the clients versus all the servers.
The more boxes you tick in that matrix,
the better. Now, the question is,
what is that connexion you are ticking?
So for that,
you have certain scenarios or use cases.
So in our case,
the servers will be one or more provider
directories,
and I don't know what the clients will be.
So this is our task, to say,
these are a few interesting activities,
and here's our matrix,
and we hope you have fun trying to
connect these systems up.
Sometimes people start at a lower level
and just want to experience what
connecting actually means.
So that changes from the original
connect-a-thon idea,
and maybe we're in that bracket.
So that's what it is.
It's meant to be appropriate to the
people who will be attending in their
interests.
Roughly.
Yeah.
If I, can I just add to that?
Just so I agree with you completely,
Yeah.
Yoongi,
about that being the normal pattern for a
connect-a-thon,
but from my experience of last time and
Mm.
my wider understanding from doing the
training of
where QH is at with regard to fire.
Um, I think...
There's more likely to be value,
and this is something, Paul,
I'm really happy for you to decide.
I don't think many people are going to
come with already pre-prepared.
software systems ready to test,
I don't think we're at that place.
So I think we're more at the place of,
can we stand up, in this case,
a provider directory?
EN.
Somehow query it and establish a proof of
concept of what could be done within QH.
So I think,
I personally think that's the likely
direction that's going to get traction,
but I'm really open to be corrected on
Help.
that. And Paula, but I haven't said,
like last time,
nobody really had any idea what they were
coming in for.
And so it's a matter of providing a bit
of direction of engaging people with, wow,
They.
this would be a useful tool,
and look what we could do in two days,
standing up a proof of concept.
So I think that's the model that we might
Guy.
be best to follow,
but I'm open to correction on that.
Yeah.
what's going on in QH.
I can do the technical. If somebody says,
oh,
we want to set up a provider directory.
Yes.
Yeah.
Here you go, plop.
So,
so setting up provider directories and
any fire servers is very easy to do.
It is relatively easy to do with the
tools that I have at the end. Yeah.
No, it's it.
Yeah,
I've built several recently and really
big ones as well.
It's getting easier and easier now.
EN.
The problem I had at the last session I
went to was actually the infrastructure
in the room.
allowing you to actually create,
because if you're going to create these
servers, you need to create networks,
you need to create logins,
you need to create...
Whole systems, you know,
and especially if you've got three or
four servers in your own fire server.
So if you've got an IMER system,
a pathology system, radiology system,
then an interoperability system.
Got 4 Postgres databases.
Fire interfaces made me happy, whatever.
And then somebody comes along and says,
can you actually connect to that?
Technically,
you should be able to connect to any REST
API easily if you've got the right
credentials to actually hit the system.
In terms of the system actually working,
they should have tested the system.
Quite considerably to see that it accepts
the commands, and...
The problem I've now added to that is the
problem of what does QH require?
In terms of provider directory,
I was actually looking,
I need.
actually built one.
which we could use Postman and Hit,
or you could use the,
there's a GUI as well where you could
just log in and see what providers there
were and kick off a workflow.
So if you wanted a cardiology,
if you wanted a cardiology provider,
dermatology provider, all those things,
you can set up hundreds and hundreds.
of different providers and organizations.
But then I thought, well,
smart referrals handles all that really
coming from the GPs into the HSE.
So.
Just reflected on that probably in the
last couple of hours and thought,
you know, how does that really work?
It doesn't, and then in terms of...
what we're taking into the room.
for people to try and connect to.
You know,
the last one we had the providers and,
you know, vendors coming from Singapore,
Hong Kong, but the systems were...
Weren't really that useful.
And I didn't see much interoperability in
the end in terms of...
Mm.
Yeah.
I'm a bit lost at what we're trying to...
Ohh.
You know,
if people from Queensland Health are
coming into the room.
You know,
they could build applications on the fly
if they're clever enough.
I did it the last one. You know,
you can build apps faster than, you know,
and I built several apps to join to the
vendors pieces in the room. However,
the infrastructure let, you know,
you know, I was blocked from several.
because the back at their back ends
couldn't handle the amount of hits they
were getting and things. But anyway,
what do you want to do and...
I mean, based on that experience,
the core...
I.
Locker.
that we would need to resolve is the
performance of the underlying
infrastructure that we're basing our
segment on.
And I can chase that if you want.
Yeah, so, you know,
I considered just putting container. Well,
So that's.
the model, the most recent one,
I've just put Docker,
Docker containers and put, you know,
released,
Yes.
and that's probably the safest way to do
it.
Yeah,
so I would either put K3S's in or compose
this.
Steel.
But I think the bigger question which
you're raising, Paul, is...
O.
is what are we trying to do that's going
to engage people?
Yeah.
Yeah, I...
And I think until we work that out,
the other stuff we can absolutely need to
Yes.
do. But I'm not clear on,
so if you've built a provider directory
Yeah.
or multiple versions thereof,
I presume you've built something that's
appropriate for QH already, is that right?
Well, no, I, because the brief,
the brief I got was,
this is the track we're doing, you know,
provider directory,
and then they wanted a workflow kicking
off from that.
It was then actually looking at how I
could put that into a use case within
Queensland Health.
Um...
Okay.
And so, I kind of looked at it back.
So, where did the idea come from?
Do you know?
I haven't had any input on this track
whatsoever.
No, no, I think none of us have, have we?
No, and I wouldn't have chosen it.
What?
Ohh...
So, what I mean, we are free still to,
it's not locked in.
So if we don't have a vision for it,
I'm not saying we shouldn't look at it
first,
but if we don't and we've got vision for
something else.
It's much better to get something that's
going to engage people at QH.
If it's just been an idea from outside
that someone said, let's do it provided.
So I know there's a national effort going
on around revamping the...
The provider IG,
but that has a very specific set of
requirements,
and that's something that's going to be
developed outside of QH anyway,
at a national level. So, I mean,
Yeah.
if that was already available and we
wanted to hook into it using FHIR that...
And we had use cases around that,
that would be a valid way of doing it,
I have tested it at the last connector.
Yes, it's working,
but I don't.
Have you?
EN.
but its capability statement was broken
at the time.
Okay, so I mean,
that's a possibility if that,
but is that meaningful on a QH side to be
doing that?
Or are you going to be using internal
systems?
What is our actual,
what is our actual boundary? Like,
Goodbye.
what's the top level heading that our
segment has?
Are we already nailed down and labelled
provider directory?
Okay.
Or do we still have some wiggle room?
I would understand.
I'm happy to go back to Jim and say...
We don't have a clear,
none of us have a clear sense of
direction, if that's where we end up.
But I'd like to go back and just say,
Here's a suggestion or something that we
can work on that involves setting up some
operations, involves some IG profiling,
some front-end work to produce a useful
application by the end or proof of
concept by the end of that time.
Yeah.
So...
That, to me,
that would be the thing that we should
aim to do that I can see of being of
value, but Paul,
Yeah.
you might see something much more
valuable. Please,
I'm just jumping in here with my limited
vision.
Yeah.
But we'll let.
Let me show you what I've got.
Kate.
As opposed to...
Do you have share permissions?
Let me just check.
Um...
Now you should have share permissions.
Thanks very much.
How do I pronounce your name?
Um, yearn ghee,
like yearning and Indian butter.
Young Guy.
You're heading for Indian butter?
I like it.
Thanks.
Help to remember.
And I, I'm having a guess, but it's...
from the southern continent.
Not quite.
It's a mix of French and German.
And you?
Yeah.
Okay, cool.
Blame the 70s where everybody was in love
with each other, or 60s rather.
Yeah.
Well, I'm from the 60s,
so there's nothing wrong with them.
Oh, I'm not suggesting that at all.
I'm just,
the interesting composition was my
parents basically saying he can choose
his name and gender later. So
Right.
Excellent, I, but I, I wasn't that lucky.
Yes.
So, I'm a staley, maily, paley.
Yeah.
That's how it turned out by default.
Okay, so.
Yes.
So, we basically just built something,
you know, a whole package.
Following,
just following a kind of a previous
project, so...
But I don't know if it's actually giving
us anything.
You know,
we can look at the provider directory.
Ohh.
Behind it, but...
I, you know,
last time when I kind of brought some
stuff along.
It wasn't what people wanted.
Just jump in.
Yeah, I wanted to make a pitch.
How about we turn the elephant on its
back and talk about how people can learn
to run services so that, yeah,
this is really easy,
is actually owned by everyone.
Because I think the perception that a lot
of people have is
Oh, this is so hard.
So I've got this Akadaka project,
which is a really big collection of
different...
recipes for pre-configured fire servers.
They're all Docker compose recipes.
And they, I don't know, one as there's,
I've got one that has HL 7,
Yeah.
I've got one that has a terminology
server,
I've got one that has a validation
interceptor.
They all have an associated tutorial
where you can learn.
What that fire thing is, and whether it...
Like, rocks your boat in some way,
but we could we could explain it,
Well, well, well.
and then they could try.
Try to run their own thing.
Who's the audience though for that?
That's the,
Yeah.
when I've been in the room with you guys
before,
It it it doesn't.
You know,
the people who want to really use fire
normally come in as novices and get
totally overwhelmed by such things that,
Yeah.
you know,
it is easy for us to implement any kind
of fire server and interoperability and
to put, you know,
facades in front of existing data and
Mm.
You know, get them communicating.
Well...
Who's gonna be in the room?
I don't even know that.
So, from my experience, we'll get about...
Twenty-five percent of the group who are
mostly, or maybe a little less,
mostly clinical.
We're gonna get about.
Fifty percent who are kind of in project
management, interested in fire,
possibly architecture,
but are not developers,
and about 25% developers. So,
that's the difference with the
Connectathon.
You're usually getting 90% developers
Yeah.
with a few subject matter experts to
flesh it out.
And I think this time we can't expect
that unless we've got a pre-selected
group. So I think I agree with you, Paul.
Help.
Yes.
We can't go to, I really like the idea,
Genghi,
of providing people a whole lot of
different snapshots,
but if they don't even have the basics.
I almost wonder, this is just spitballing,
okay? So please say it's rubbish,
Mm.
but I wonder if we could...
Step back from your example, Paul,
and just talk about the main steps that
you go through in developing something
such as you have done, and do a kind of a.
..
tutorial where they fill out the blanks
and where we get different people and we
can get some people working on, well,
what are the most likely requirements
we're going to have for the actual
practitioner role.
profile in QH and you can get a team
working on the data side,
Ohh.
the specification.
You can get a team working on the front
end.
and some other people creating or working
with synthetic data.
to populate it,
doing fire queries on REST APIs.
It's just an idea,
but it's a way of using the work that
you've already done.
letting them hopefully come up with it
with something that might be as good as
Ops.
what you've already done at the end of
the day,
Feiyu.
but seeing how to do something like that.
I like the idea of having a main use case.
So I was wondering if we can do the main
use case and then do.
I don't know, due to the side,
do a smorgasbord,
like list all the things that you can
have in Fire use case.
Mm.
And then here is the example.
And if anybody says, OK,
we are really interested in that thing,
then we'll just patch.
One of us to do the specific that they
want to veer to,
but otherwise the main run will be.
A teaching style, detailed walkthrough.
to do one well-prepared use case.
So what's the world's best example?
The gold standard, no,
I'm asking you now directly,
give me the number one use case for fire
in health services.
Which?
Probably patient administration.
Replacing hibiscus.
Pre-filled forms.
Replacing hibiscus.
So, let's go back.
****.
I wasn't necessarily saying we should do
it,
but I was telling you what is the number
one use case.
So just been involved with data bricks
who are actually not replacing it.
This is how bad things are.
They've actually just migrated.
Copies of it across, so...
Right,
but it's that in the whole world of fire
that's...
What's the biggest,
who's the biggest user of it?
Who's the biggest user of Feiyu?
Yeah.
Well, the...
US Insurers.
Yeah,
the big EMRs all have fire interfaces,
epic CNN, blah, blah, blah,
just about everybody does. And
Except Australia.
Well, yeah, been a bit slow, but I mean,
S&A has it, but for some reason...
Um...
It doesn't have very much. I tested it.
It's very restricted in its resources.
We tried to put a deployed system onto it
and despite...
Yeah.
was like we couldn't implement it because
the resource types were too constrained.
Yeah.
Hmm.
So we're not deploying that.
And that's not an that's probably true
for both Epic and Senna,
because they're trying to protect their
own.
Yeah.
Hum.
Central core, because the sooner, yeah,
'cause if you can do it on fire,
The Bratrick.
people go, why do we pay?
Epic has closed the sandbox.
You can't get to it anymore.
Yeah.
So.
You can if you're in Epic if you're
paying them lots of money, but yeah.
SAP.
So the reality for Queensland Health is
that anything which is really embedded in
IMER at the moment is not going to
benefit from.
Feiyu.
That's not necessarily true.
So I can speak for a project I'm involved
Yeah.
with. So we've got...
possibly the first deployment of a fire
service in, in this case,
the children's hospital.
We're running a separate fire server and
the direction this is heading into is
probably a more professional second tier
fire server that's fed out of the data
warehouse and out of IEMR.
So that's where the data is going to be
coming from.
So people will benefit from it,
but they will not usually directly
interact with IMR for load reasons and
for lack of interface. So the solutions
Do not will not directly sit sit on
Millennium IMR.
Yeah.
And what's the solution? Is that that?
But this is a drug bug matching thing for
the emergency.
So the thing is you order tests,
like you see a patient, a child,
and you order tests,
the tests are not coming back immediately.
You discharge.
And on Monday,
the tests come in and they tell you, look,
first of all,
what you've given them is not effective.
You need to call them immediately.
They're actually,
there's something better you should give
them.
You should change what you've got or
you're spot on. This is the right thing.
So in all cases, you sign off.
that you've seen the advice and the
solution sorts the advice in such a way
that high-risk advice is at the very top
of your list to sign off.
And if you have something to act,
then you can act from that interface and
it will then allow you to
Contact the patient.
create follow-up appointment and that
sort of thing.
So that pushes back into the regular
system.
So it doesn't handle those things itself.
It just makes transactionally sure that
the follow-up process is enacted.
On.
Help.
So, it's an adjunct,
you're taking data out of the main system
That's.
and doing something here, and then, yeah.
Essentially, yes.
And when there is multiple staff on it,
Yeah.
then updates are being passed.
So if there's five people following up on
the Monday and three have worked this
case,
then the solution will see they've done
this and will push back to the interface
and take the cases out.
because they've already been dealt with,
so two people don't need to work on the
same thing.
reduces the turnaround time,
and we've validated it with actual staff.
So now we're heading to deployment.
So the two business cases, Paul,
just for a large organization,
large healthcare organization,
to actually move to fire.
tend to be, number one,
there's something that needs replacing
desperately like hibiscus.
and you've therefore got not a complete
greenfields,
but you've got a business necessity for
change anyway,
that's going to be quite significant.
So that provides the trigger.
And on the other hand,
it tends to be the kinds of things that
Nguyen Guy is talking about,
where you've got
Either a specific.
disease type workflow that is unique or
some kind of management medications like
OK.
Nguyen Guy was talking about that isn't
going to be able to easily be supported
in your existing EMR system.
So you extract information out,
process it, push it back in again.
and have a little bit on the side as well
with all the extra detail on it.
Bye.
So those tend to be the two ways that a
large organisation engages with FHIR.
Nobody is going to quickly jump in and
make everything FHIR compliant.
The other thing you can do is if you've
got a...
strong messaging system in the backbone,
you can actually start to populate a FHI
server with valid up-to-date patient
records and things like that that you can
then use for all kinds of other new
applications that you're putting in place.
But yeah.
All for use cases,
I've put in my fire patterns website in
Yeah.
the chat, which is a...
Excellent.
a classic design patterns website to the
same pattern language,
but with three different topic areas that
are nested, that are associated.
And I think the first one, implementation,
might be the one that you'd be most
interested in. It
planes use cases on the level of prior
architecture. So I don't know,
typical use case. Imaging integration,
for example, is one that always comes up.
But.
Well, that's...
That's,
so I'm being an SIBT at the moment is,
you know, I'm just...
been dealing with MICSU,
which is the Medical Imaging Central
Support Unit.
So there is a huge use case for the rest
Yeah.
systems to talk to each other.
Yeah,
so I've just put in the imaging category.
Let me place that here.
Oh, it has grabbed the imaging, sorry.
Um...
Ohh yeah, this is better.
There, now you've got it.
So that's the overview for the imaging
category and it has...
Typical.
design patterns that often come up with
its related resources,
the way this website works.
It's too high a level for what we are
But...
going to do,
but what it does is it groups typical
design patterns together,
shows what their relationships are,
and their advantages and disadvantages.
And then you can...
Select from them and build your solution.
Each of those languages has an agent's MD
file on top,
so you can point your agent at the top
level address and say there is an agent's
MD,
and then you can talk to your agent in
order to develop the architecture.
Yeah.
The other two languages are for...
Doing the implementation projects,
and they talk about project management.
Just, just, just.
Yeah, I appreciate that.
Just look in the architecture diagram for,
Yeah.
you know,
imaging integration architecture real
time.
It does a does a, you know,
it links to EMR systems straight off the
bat in the architecture. Now,
the reality is that doesn't happen.
No.
These systems are absolutely siloed,
and we're not talking about just in the
Yeah.
in our ecosystem.
We're actually utilising work with with
outsourcing to private companies as well,
so the request has to go.
right,
could possibly go to this risk system,
that risk system, one outside the system.
And the loop back is the thing which is
concerning everybody.
Because even with your system,
you're talking at the children's data
coming out,
doing something with it and pushing it
back in.
If something gets missed on the way out.
You are never,
you don't have visibility to it in your
external fire system.
And that's what happened, that's where,
you know,
that's normally when a child dies and
somebody says, well, it didn't go out,
you know, for whatever reason.
And that's what happens.
Yeah.
That's what happens with medical imaging
all the time is, you know,
ET.
Well,
you're talking of transactional design,
Things that.
is that right?
Like, if that's the name you give it,
then that's...
Well,
a transaction means that either your
transfer of data is...
I've just got to answer the door;
I'll be back.
Help.
It's really interesting, Nguyen Guy.
I'm going to have a look through these.
I've done quite a bit of work with
imaging and stuff because I work for
I, yeah.
Phillips and that's their bread and
butter.
I think you will like the other two
languages better.
Mm.
look at those because they are management
related,
they are for IG project management.
So they describe how to set up a project
to create an implementation guide and how
to
Mm.
All of the implementation guide itself,
so they are basically for creating new
implementation guide work.
And because I know you do that.
Mm.
I like.
Yeah, I like the on your back.
Yeah, no,
that's been my bread and butter for a
long time, so...
Yeah, I, I would like,
that's that's I would like, you know,
medical imaging would be a useful use
case, because...
At the moment,
we've got very basic HL7 messaging,
Yeah.
Mmh.
you know, coming back on some systems,
but on most of them, as you know,
you know, we've got faxes going across,
we've got scanning of documents back into
IMER, we've got, you know,
just such a mixed.
Mhm.
And if we want true interoperability
between AFCA, you know, you know, Sultan,
Oh.
Radiology Plus,
and then all the external providers as
well,
like that would be a real good use case.
Mhm.
So I think what you've been working with
is what you said. So most of there is,
or everywhere system that I know has an
HL7 interface,
which is what it primarily uses to keep
in sync with other patient administration
information. It's pretty basic,
as you say.
But usually you've got patient
information, order information, study.
Study completion.
Yeah,
a session number has all that kind of
That's, and that's about,
that's about all you can get. Look,
thing.
it's easy enough to make up a fire repo
that does that.
But I don't know,
but is that going to be something that
grabs people for the connect-a-thon?
If it is, let's work on it.
Happy to do that.
One.
I don't know what the aim of the
Connector Fund is,
EN.
to get something valuable and tangible
for the organisation or just to create
another fun session of...
My suggestion is it needs to be tangible
for the participants.
Mmh.
Yeah, so I...
It doesn't have to be that it produces a
production-ready or remotely
production-ready system at the end.
It's more that everybody goes away
understanding this is how you go about it,
whether it is creating a set of workflows
Help.
So.
that we model using an IG,
we interact with.
Using A front-end and some REST API stuff,
so I personally think that's the scope
that's realistic for two days.
I'm super happy to have it in whatever
area you, Paul,
think is the best to go with.
Today,
I'm not constrained to doing provider
I, I'm.
No.
directory,
but I think what you've done with
provider directory is a good,
if we break it apart into the steps that
you went through and walk people through
there and get them to develop it
themselves in different parts and see if
we can plug it all in together at the end.
And if that doesn't work,
we can show yours and say, hey,
look what we didn't.
Ohh.
Well, no, I quite like, given the context,
you just put the connector phone in there
in terms of working through.
I then quite like the Akadaka, you know.
Okay, that's cool.
And I think we just need to then script
And I think...
out what is the use case,
get some sample HL7 messages,
get somebody doing the transformation of
HL7 to REST interactions.
Well, this is why I posted that.
That's a ready to use HL7 fire facade
I.
that does fire mappings and can be
manipulated to do messages of other types.
Mm.
The only thing that we may need to think
about
is that it uses,
it's actually intended to attach to a
live HL7 system,
so it speaks the specific network
Yeah.
protocol for fire message for HLV2
messages. I've programmed it that way.
Yeah, but that's not, that's not, I mean,
we can set up a little server,
Yeah.
Mm.
Yeah.
a laptop that is feeding the, you know,
you're just dropping in files with the
EER.
Yeah.
HL7 message and it wraps them in MLP and
sends them to a TCP address somewhere. So.
Yeah.
It's interesting because it internally
uses a lot of the concepts of Fire.
So it's got the way it works is it reads.
Yeah.
a message and turns it into a fire
resource, which is just a big fat string.
Yeah.
Yes, yeah.
And then it sticks on top of it a grammar
based on a few bytes and breaks that
resource down into a more complicated one.
And from that,
it uses terminology cheques
To make sure that the data matches
terminology and then uses fire
Mm.
transformations.
to transform what came in into stuff in
the server.
So that's its architecture here.
So it's got a lot of...
You can just reuse that sort of thing and
it shows that fire doesn't have to be
arrested. It can also be messages.
And that would actually fit quite well
with the other use case that the guys
from the SID team have suggested,
which is using CSIRO HL7 messages to
Ops.
create.
to create a register of appointments for
our patient work. So, I mean,
Mm.
we could work on two tracks quite
similarly, if that works.
That sounds really sexy.
So we could have one where the mess where
people are dropping messages in a sender.
We'll just have a machine that sends HR7
Yeah.
messages and just makes them up.
You type some things in.
EN.
It shows you what that message is.
And then if you say,
Yeah.
like it shows you the buffer,
how it's assembled,
Yeah.
you push the button and it goes and sends
it to this receiver hub.
Yeah.
And the receiver then tries to do that.
And we show them the application and then
they can try their own application.
They can try their own HL7 message sender
Mm.
if they want. Or they can
Create a new message type.
Like, instead of this,
it will receive that,
or they go from the other side and they
attach to the file server that receives
them.
and write an application that shows
whatever has been received.
So there we have all the bits of a Fire
Connectathon quite literally,
And yeah.
like we've got people hacking on,
getting messages in,
we give them some to actually try to
like make a front end to try to send
messages.
Yeah.
To change the server, run the server.
Yep.
query the server,
and we'll explain this one case in detail
and say, yes, there's tonnes of others.
Talk to us in the break,
or talk to Joern Guy in the breakout,
and he can.
Give you some detail.
Cool.
But what we're doing in this one is we
want to focus on this,
and all our trainers are knowledgeable of
this scenario.
Yeah,
and the only other thing I'd add to that
is you could have one group who are just
working on developing the IG that
describes the transformation from the
particular HL7 message through to the...
Yeah.
This one has an IG,
so they can use that as an example.
Yeah.
They can clone this repository.
It's got an IG in it.
Yeah.
Pretty sure I made an IG. Let me see.
No, there's no one.
It's just that there'll be,
you'll have to do it for each specific
You will have to, yeah, you will have to.
message type. And so I think I...
So I'd certainly look at what you've done,
but I think, you know, we just,
and that can be something we can do some
initial work on,
either using your work or my prior work
in terms of creating a template that
people can adapt rather than having to
start from scratch with an IG.
Yeah, I think we should ask them to clone.
Now,
Mhm.
I think that the pivotal point for all of
this is to make sure people can actually
do the hacking. So network.
accessibility, DNS.
these sorts of things. They are,
I think that's the blocker as far as I
can see.
And...
I just think there's going to be
different people working on different
aspects because some people are not going
to get to that.
Oh, I...
If you start talking DNS with a person
with clinical background,
Ohh, no, yeah, no.
their eyes will glaze over.
So I think we need to have separate roles
Yes.
that we identify.
Within the group.
But from our, from the magic we'll show,
like the magic comes from people actually
It.
If...
being able to push a button and go, whoo,
I did this.
Mm.
So our system in the back end has to work,
I think.
Like if the servers can't connect,
that's not a satisfactory outcome.
That's what I'm saying.
Absolutely. Yeah, no,
I don't disagree with you at all. I just,
That's why I'm saying this is the blocker.
yeah.
But.
And then need the computers that people
are bringing along. Obviously, that's,
you know,
QH computers are just going to be a big
no-no.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's where the Docker doesn't work,
That's right.
so what I need to figure out is a is a
model that allows them.
to do this, I need to think about,
rapidly think about,
figure out what there is,
like what we will have at hand,
and then think about, then ask QH,
what will the laptops be?
What constraints will they be working
under?
What are the permissions that they have?
And then
come to a development model where people
can actually hack.
In some way.
Is there gonna be enough people with that
level?
Yeah, I...
A third.
I, I'd be concerned that there won't be.
Yeah.
Fourth, a quarter, a third.
I, I, I think you're going high.
Yeah.
Really? Okay.
So, 1/4 is 5 people.
I...
That's 2 teams, three and two.
Yeah.
I might be underselling this,
but I think you're going to be lucky to
Um...
get 5.
Yeah.
So my suggestion would be in terms of
Yeah.
infrastructure that we have,
we have to have accessibility for people
Demo.
to do basic REST queries against whatever
server we do.
Because I think that's an important part.
Some people will never get any further
Mm.
than knowing a few postman queries.
And I'm happy with it.
So do we do this solution in beautiful
and tutorial it apart with people playing
Kate.
against it?
Yeah, and then I think we need some,
we need something which is...
Is that what we want to do?
I la.
Is cloud hosted where you can put...
The.
The backend processes that you've talked
about, Nguyen Guy,
Yeah.
and then with an API to post to get those
underway,
and I think we can leave it very open.
We can have it just available for the two
Well, that's what I mean.
days, so it's really unlikely that...
someone will do anything security wise
that will damage it and we can just leave
it open for the QH.
This is a suggestion, okay?
I'm just spitballing again.
But I think that might be a way we could
do it. Does that make sense or not?
I mean,
I don't like leaving things open
Um...
security-wise,
but then usually all of our fire servers
that we use in Connectathons are wide
open anyway, so...
If it's an example,
all we need to tell them is not to put
any real data in.
Yeah.
So let me,
so let's just let's just look at the
vision and then I'll see if I can get on
to making the making it real.
Yeah.
So what we want is we want to do a guided
tutorial.
Tutorial.
And we'll take that HL7 facade example
and extend it a bit on both ends.
We'll have a website that is a submitter.
where people can first try random strings.
Maybe there's a little bit of a guided
one.
It says it's got fields and it shows them
the HL7 message, how it's being composed,
and they can send from there.
Then we have.
the server,
it receives those messages and we have a
peer application that shows the error log
or whatever is happening.
So it shows the message was received,
this message was received and it errored
in this particular way.
So people can correlate and they can have
a look. I just sent this.
What happened?
And then we'll have a third site that
sort of...
logs onto the server and it's the fire
server as we know with a little bit of a
drape and they can see what they sent.
So they've got the experience of sending
HL7v2 the old stuff that gets mixed,
transformed and then they can...
Have a look at the other side,
a long example, and we will.
Explain to them the different parts and
how they work, piece by piece.
Is that good? Is that what we would like?
All of it hosted somewhere.
So they can use it and retry it again and
we'll give them source code.
So in the last module you're talking
about,
that would be something that's basically
a simple front end that would,
for example,
you'd be able to look up a patient and
identify all of the radiology studies
that
they've had times and dates and that kind
of thing,
Something like that.
or in the case of the appointment thing,
yeah, I think,
Yeah, whatever you want, like a...
and I think there has to be some room for
the developers to jump in and to build
those out.
Mmh.
But if we've got...
Yeah, so we'll just have source code.
Paula, how is that sounding to you?
Because it's all very well for you and
Guy and I think ideas, but...
Ohh, no, I, I,
I'm led by you fellas on this, I'll be,
Well, no,
I think we really need to know if it's
but, but...
fitting for your direction too.
But if you want to spin it back to the
provider directory,
Yeah.
you could actually then have different
providers of modality of the service,
you know, in terms of CT, MRI.
You could read it back to the
Mm.
the provider directory and initiate
workflows as well.
Yeah.
Mhm.
Can I ask you, but...
So,
are you suggesting that instead of doing
the the risk stuff or?
No, no, I'm as an add-on to the register.
As an add-on, yeah. Look,
I think it's a great idea. I just,
Ohh.
knowing how little you get through in two
days.
I guess you could have an advanced group
working on that.
Well, no, I, I was trying to,
I was trying to provide a point.
to just sending HL7 messages.
Yes.
And looking at error logs and then
looking at the GUI front end of, you know,
the fire server they're being sent to.
No,
I'm just trying to link it back to the
Kate.
provider directory.
Did the private, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
no, it's good. Well...
So, okay.
You have the link to that.
That example,
the HL7 example source code and what it
can do.
Um...
I would like, if we can do it this way,
you to work on the, no,
I really don't like that word,
but on the vision of it.
So go through what the teaching workflow
is going to be,
what the various pieces of the scenario
are going to be,
and come back with the requirements on
the architecture to me.
And I will go sideways in the meantime
and look at the infrastructure that we
have on site.
What sort of network do we have external
access? Can we get a cloud?
These sorts of things.
How can we actually deploy a solution in
that workshop so people can use it?
And then I hope we get a second meeting
lined up.
Yeah.
You.
The other thing that I would like is a
place where we can share information.
I'm not sure how,
what the best way to do that is.
I don't think we've got any, yeah,
between us.
Between us or be with?
So I can see your updates and your
thinking as you write documents.
So I think...
I think Claire set up a team site.
Yeah.
Ah, and you are on the team side.
And we can, yeah,
are you able to access that, Paul?
Yeah.
Okay, I think I've got that.
Let me just see. So is it...
If enabling fire is the connector, so...
Fire and QH Connect is on 2026.
Track 2, that's us. Track 2.
That's where we are.
Is that correct?
Let me just...
Yeah, track 25 for services.
So I think that's open for us to put
Yes.
whatever we want in there.
Can you put a sham file in?
Just do you have access to it?
Can you just put a bogus file in so we
know that the communication works on it?
I'll do that. Just give me a moment.
This is not necessarily a useful file,
but it was something that I just started.
Doing some work on.
PDF.
Five minutes.
Yeah.
Sorry,
I hadn't even saved what I was working on,
so...
Is he gone?
Do you want me to touch a file?
But it doesn't prove much.
Yeah.
I need you to touch the file.
Oh, where is it gone? Yeah, sorry,
I'm having difficulty here.
Must have gone into downloads.
Ops.
So the requirements on infrastructure are
for us to have a network that can access
the services and for the client,
clients from their laptops to access the
services for review.
And then potentially as a second tier,
some means for people to develop services
and also make them available to others.
That second one we expect that's going to
be 5 people and I should probably target
them directly so I see what they've got.
So I'll see how we can communicate with
the actual developers.
So I put it in track two,
it's called First Thoughts, Daniel,
So.
so please just feel free to ignore the
contents,
but it was just some random thoughts
before I got started.
Great, okay.
And for Paul, it will be the same. Good,
then we've got everything now,
You can see it.
so if I get, if I get a summary.
Yeah, I can, I can say.
Ohh.
So Paul, can we get you to...
Anything.
start to elaborate the idea around the
risk stuff.
And I'll get in touch with Darren
Plumridge and see if I can elaborate some
stuff around the appointment.
And.
Yeah,
I'm interested in the appointment one in
terms of what they're trying to do.
Because the appointments, the schedulings,
or in IMT, I don't.
Yeah, only for inpatient.
No, it's for surgical outpatients as well.
My wife uses it every day.
So there's a bunch of stuff that doesn't
get captured that he was saying that
they're wanting to try and capture in a
consistent manner.
Yeah.
But it's also really just a trial proof
of concept.
Yeah.
So it doesn't need to go anywhere. So,
and by all means,
if you've got better ideas, please say.
I'm just, I'm
No, no, I no.
I'm an outside party just trying to find
something that will be as useful as
Well...
possible to you guys and want to work
with you on that.
So please feel free to be directive here,
Paul.
The other thing that I wanted to bring up
is timelines.
Oh.
By what time I could expect a design that
you to come up with if...
Okay, so here's the difficulty,
Nguyen Guy. I don't know your situation,
If...
Paul, but I'm a contractor.
So,
I'm contracted to do 2 days for the
Connectathon and a few hours preparation
work.
I really don't have a huge amount of time
to give to it,
because not just because I'm not paid for
it,
but because I do have other work as well.
But I'm basically,
I don't think I should have been put in
as a track lead for that reason,
but I was put in without being asked.
So I'm doing my best here.
Well,
if somebody can send me examples of
Mm.
what's been done in the past,
then that would help A lot. You know,
What's been, yeah.
Yeah, and I'm not trying to cop out,
don't get me wrong.
I'm lacking clarity. No, no.
I will do my absolute best to come up
with things,
but I can't spend the huge amounts of
time elaborating that I normally would do
if I was coming to a connect-a-thon.
Bye.
from an organisation and wanting to
contribute what I've been working on.
Mm.
Yeah.
The other thing that my management brain
says we need to have a head.
Do any of you want to take the
responsibility to drive this tick?
No, I'm quite happy for you to drive it.
Okay, Daniel, do you want to drive it?
Because they certainly don't want to,
Yeah, I think, look,
I think we need to get back to Jim about
but if I'm the only person...
this because it's problematic that...
Yeah.
None of us are really in a place to have
a clear.
I've got to jump into another meeting as
well, but I totally agree with you.
Energy.
Yeah.
All right.
I haven't got a clear concept of what the
thing's about. I think, yeah,
Good.
I'm being led.
But if you send me some examples,
Good.
So I will,
I'm really happy to advise and to give
input,
but I can't take a management role in
this and that I think that's what we're
needing here. So I let me,
Bye.
So...
unless you want to do it, Nguyen Guy,
but I think we need to raise it with Jim,
escalate it as an issue.
because I think it wasn't really thought
through the putting us all as track leads
when we've all got other things on.
That's right.
It'd be good if we had another person,
Well, I...
I think, as well. I've got to go. Sorry,
I'll catch up with you next time.
Yeah, so...
Okay.
See ya, thanks for, yeah, thanks, bye.
Okay, thanks. Thank you.
Thanks very much.
Um...
Daniel,
I think because you are currently the
track lead,
you should go back to Jim and tell him
what the issue is.
And if you,
if they want to pass the hat to anybody,
if they get somebody else,
I think realistically it's unlikely.
Yeah.
And you want to,
and the agreement is to pass the hat to
me because they need a driver.
then that's what we'll do.
I just think it would turn into an issue
Yeah.
if we were not going to deliver the track.
And for...
I totally agree with you,
and I think I think it's really important
Yeah, for age, I see the name stuck.
that it be something.
That has at least some pull factor from
Queensland Health,
Yeah.
and if Paul is not secure on that.
I'm really concerned because I understood
that this whole idea of provider
directory was something that had a pull
factor from QH and it doesn't sound like
it does.
So now the only thing that remains is the
question whether you want me to be in
that conversation that will slow us down
or whether you want to do it on your own,
which means we travel faster.
Let me do the initial conversation.
If I'm getting stuck,
Jim is a hard man to pin down.
So if I get stuck,
Yeah.
I might have to reach out to you.
But I really like him,
I get on well with him,
and we've worked close together.
But he has a very different
perception of just showing up and other
people driving something,
which I don't think is going to work in
this context.
So would you agree with that?
I think we need some direction that says
this is the way we're doing it.
And to a large degree,
the other two tracks are driven by people
from
who are working in the space within CSIRO,
who are spending all their time working
on that.
So it's just a tutorial for what they're
doing.
But ours is a little different from that
regard.
Yeah.
OK, let me pick it up. If you don't,
let's try and have a follow-up meeting.
Mm.
in a few days time because I think...
But I'll try and get in touch with Jim
prior to that.
Yes.
I'll send him a message today and we'll
try and tee up a time to talk.
So the two blocking things are, for me,
getting infrastructure because we need it
anyway.
Yes.
And for you,
the red hot one is to talk to Jim and say,
we're all at loose ends and we need to
tie them up quickly.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, indeed.
Yeah.
Okay, good.
Hey, thank you. And I really,
I love the work you're doing.
I would love to have a bit longer to
actually explore it and just say,
Well, maybe.
I think there's probably quite a bit of
overlap with some of the things I've done,
but you approach it from a really...
Much more, how shall I say?
Logic-driven.
Yeah, top pattern approaches,
and I love that, but I tend to...
LMS.
I'm a software engineer,
what do you expect?
Yeah, well, I am too from background,
but I still...
Yeah.
A lot of my, I'm an architect primarily,
and so my skill set is,
Mm.
you always have to have a certain amount
of...
of intuitive approach to get a high-level
architecture in place and to think
outside the square. Not that you don't,
but just I value people like yourselves
Yes.
who can rationalise it and come up with
these things.
So thank you for sharing it and I'll get
back to you.
and to Paul about what,
how am I meeting with Jim Guy?
Very good.
Anything I get out of that automated tool
Okay.
I will put into that drive.
Thank you very much. Much appreciated.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you. Have a great one.
Thanks for that. Bye.
Kiss.
Yeah, you too. Bye bye.